Guide to the Taylor Family Papers, 1850-1975
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library Duke University Durham, N.C., USA
Taylor family papers 1850-1975 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library, Duke University
Taylor Family.
0.6 Linear Feet 500 Items
Missionaries to Nigeria for the Southern Baptist Foreign Missions Board, 1955-1962.
Family letters, photographs, and diaries from the Taylor family's mission work in Nigeria and their return voyage to the United States. Also includes a selection of photocopied letters from T. J. Bowen to James A. Taylor, 1850-1867, documenting Bowen's life as a missionary to Africa.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. There may be a 24-hour delay in obtaining these materials.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The Taylor Family Papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 2013.
Biographical Note
Duke alumnus Orville Walters "Tom" Taylor (Ph.D., 1956) and his wife, Evelyn Taylor, went as missionary teachers to Nigeria with their son Michael in 1955. While there the Taylors had three daughters: Priscilla, Melissa, and Penelope. The family returned to the United States in 1962.
Subject Headings
These are searchable subject entries for this collection. Performing a search on these subjects in the Duke University Libraries online catalog will bring up other related research materials.
Taylor, Orville Walters
Taylor, Evelyn Adella Bonham
Taylor family
Southern Baptist Convention. Foreign Mission Board
Missionaries -- Nigeria
Children of missionaries
Married people in missionary work
Nigeria -- Description and travel
Nigeria -- Social life and customs
Contents of Collection
- Papers, (1 box)
  Family letters, photographs, and diaries from the Taylor family's mission trip to Nigeria and their return voyage to the United States. Also includes a selection of photocopied letters from T. J. Bowen to James A. Taylor, 1850-1867, documenting Bowen's life as a missionary to Africa.
  - Collection and genealogical information (Box 1)
  - Evelyn Taylor's diary, 1954-1962 (Box 1)
    From appointment to the Mission Board through the first years in Nigeria.
  - "My Life," by O.W. Taylor, 1955 (Box 1)
    Autobiography written as part of Taylor's application for the Foreign Missions Board.
  - Programs, schedules, and bulletins from the Nigerian mission, 1957-1978 (Box 1)
    Includes Newton School programs, finances, political and public events in Iwo, and other memorabilia from the Taylors' work and school.
  - Newton News newsletters, 1958 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence between Michael Taylor and his parents, 1955-1960 (Box 1)
    Written from his time boarding at the Newton Memorial School.
  - Correspondence between Evelyn Taylor and her family in the United States, 1955-1962 (Box 1)
  - Itineraries and diary from the family's trip home, 1962 (Box 1)
  - O.W. Taylor's Encyclopedia of Southern History contributions re: Duke University, 1975 (Box 1)
  - Photographs from Nigeria, 1950s-1960s (Box 1)
  - Photographs from the Nigerian Baptist Missionaries reunion, undated (Box 1)
  - Taylor family photographs, undated (Box 1)
  - Correspondence from T.J. Bowen to Rev. James B. Taylor, 1850-1867 (photocopies) (Box 1)
    Includes details on Bowen's missionary work in Africa and South America, his family's health, and some discussion of the Civil War. Collected by O.W. Taylor for a research project.